Register of the Atlantic Council of the United States Records, 1950-1986
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1950-1985
  - U.S. Citizens Commission on NATO
    - U.S. Department of State (Folder 8)
    - Vouchers
      - General (Folder 9)
      - I.P.C. meeting, London, October 26-28, 1961 (Folder 10)
      - Telephones (Folder 11)
      - Western Union (Folder 12)
    - Wallace, Richard J., travel vouchers (Folder 13)
    - Warden, Alexander (Folder 14)
    - Wynn, Douglas (Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 16)
  - U.S. Committee for the Atlantic Congress
    - General (Folder 17)
    - Bank statements (Folder 18)
    - Contributions, 1961 (Folder 19)
    - Expenditures, 1961 (Folder 20)
    - Finances, 1961 (Folder 21)
    - Finances and tax information (Folder 22)
    - Income tax report, 1962 (273, Folder 1)
    - Javits, Jacob, expenses, 1962-63 (Folder 2)
    - Meetings, 1959 (Folder 3)
  - U.S. deficit (Folder 4)
  - U.S.-European relations
    - General (Folder 5)
    - Amsterdam meeting, March 1973 (Folder 6)
  - U.S. House of Representatives, Committee on Foreign Affairs, Subcommittee on International Organizations and Movements (Folder 7)
  - U.S. Information Agency
    - General (Folder 8)
    - Volunteer Speakers Services (Folder 9)
  - U.S. Military Academy, West Point, New York (Folder 10)
  - U.S. National Committee for UNESCO (Folder 11)
  - "U.S. Policy Toward the Soviet Union: A Long-Term Western Perspective, 00," August 22, 1984, 1986-20 (Folder 12)
  - U.S. political considerations, 1968 (NYU seminar, February 1968) (Folder 13)
  - U.S. representation to the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, 1961 (Folder 14)
  - U.S. trade policy, 1961-62 (Folder 15)
  - United States Youth Council (Folder 16)
  - University of California Conference, 1963 (Folder 17)
  - University Program on International Business Development
    - Advance planning (Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1967 (Folder 19)
    - Informal Advisory Committee (Folder 20)
  - Van der Bengel, Ernst (Folder 21)
  - Venezuela
    - General (Folder 22)
    - Economy, statistics (Folder 23)
    - Economy, statistics (274, Folder 1-2)
  - Vietnam statement, 1965 (Folder 3)
  - Visiting scholars in the U.S., 1968-1970 (Folder 4)
  - Voluntary agencies, register of (Folder 5)
  - Volunteer assistance (Folder 6)
  - Wallace, Richard J.
    - 1971 (Folder 7)
    - General (Folder 8-10)
    - General (275, Folder 1)
    - Appointment books, 1971-72 (Folder 2)
    - Biography (Folder 3)
    - Correspondence
      - 1962 (Folder 4)
      - 1963 (Folder 5)
      - 1964 (Folder 6)
      - 1965-67 (Folder 7)
      - 1966 (Folder 8)
      - 1967 (Folder 9)
      - 1968 (Folder 10-11)
      - 1969
        - January-June (Folder 12)
        - July-December (276, Folder 1)
      - 1970 (Folder 2-3)
      - 1971 (Folder 4)
      - 1971-72 (Folder 5)
      - 1971
        - January-March (Folder 6)
        - April-June (Folder 7)
        - July-September (Folder 8)
        - October-December (Folder 9)
      - 1972
        - January-March (Folder 10)
        - January-July (Folder 11)
        - February-October (277, Folder 1)
        - April-July (Folder 2)
        - July-December (Folder 3)
      - 1973
        - January-June (Folder 4)
        - July-December (Folder 5)
      - 1974
        - January-June (Folder 6)
        - July-December (Folder 7)
      - Avalon Foundation, 1967-68 (Folder 8)
      - Cincinnati Council on World Affairs, 1968-69 (Folder 9)
      - Deshormes, Philippe, 1968-69 (Folder 10)
      - Garwood, Ellen, 1965-1970 (Folder 11)
      - Special mailing, 1968 (Folder 12)
      - Sponsors, 1968 (278, Folder 1)
      - U.S. Information Agency, 1968 (Folder 2)
      - Utica College of Syracuse University, 1968 (Folder 3)
    - Death, 1974 (Folder 4)
    - Declaration of Paris, 1967 (Folder 5)
    - Expenses, 1968-1970 (Folder 6-8)
    - Labor study, 1971 (Folder 9)
    - Notes for, July 23, 1964 (Folder 10)
    - Remarks
      - Berea College, May 9, 1963 (Folder 11)
      - University of Louisville, April 14, 1964 (Folder 12)
    - Report, October 14, 1963 (Folder 13)
    - Speaking engagements, 1969 (Folder 14)
    - Speeches, 1967
      - Florida State University, February 20-21 (Folder 15)
      - Eureka College, March 4 (Folder 16)
      - University of Louisville, March 30 (Folder 17)
      - Drake University, May 2 (Folder 18)
    - Study of European-American Relations, 1971 (Folder 19)
  - Wallygrams
    - 1967 (Folder 20)
    - 1969 (279, Folder 1)
    - 1970 (Folder 2)
    - 1971 (Folder 3)
    - 1972 (Folder 4)
    - 1973-76 (Folder 5)
  - Walter, Ralph E., "Radio Communication and the Erosion of Communism in Eastern Europe,", 1966 (Folder 6)
  - Warden, Alexander
    - General (Folder 7)
    - "Public Attitudes Towards the Atlantic Community Con- cept,", n.d. (Folder 8)
  - Warley, T. K., "Studies in International Economic Relations: Trade in Temperate Zone Agricultural Products,", April 1972 (Folder 9)
  - Washburn, Michael, "The Peace Movement in 1978,", August 1978 (Folder 10)
  - Washington Faculty Seminar Project, 1964-66 (Folder 11)
  - Washington Post job advertisement, December 1968 (Folder 12)
  - Waters Travel Service, 1969 (Folder 13)
  - Waugh, Samuel C. (Folder 14)
  - Western Union bills, 1969 (Folder 15)
  - Westview Press, Inc. (Folder 16)
  - "What Future for the UN? An Atlantic Dialogue,", October 1977 (280, Folder 1)
  - White House Conference on International Cooperation, November-December 1965 (Folder 2)
  - White House Fellows, 1968-69 (Folder 3)
  - Wilcox, Francis O.
    - 1978 (Folder 4)
    - 1978-79 (Folder 5)
    - 1979 (Folder 6-7)
    - ACUS Program, 1977-78 (Folder 8)
    - Advisory Trade Panel, 1977-79 (281, Folder 1)
    - American Legion UN study, 1978 (Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors, memos to, 1977 (Folder 3)
    - Brandt, Willy, proposed tour, 1976 (Folder 4)
    - Brundage, Percival (Folder 5)
    - Burgess, W. Randoph, in memoriam, 1978 (Folder 6)
    - Canadian project, 1978 (Folder 7)
    - Clippings, 1979 (Folder 8)
    - Contributions from various sources, 1978 (Folder 9)
    - Corporate solicitation for financial support, 1977-78 (Folder 10)
    - Correspondence
      - 1975
        - July-December (Folder 11)
        - Various months (Folder 12)
        - Various months (282, Folder 1-2)
      - 1976
        - January-June (Folder 3)
        - July (Folder 4)
        - July-September (Folder 5)
        - August-October (Folder 6)
        - September-October (Folder 7)
        - November-December (Folder 8)
        - Various months (283, Folder 1-2)
      - 1977
        - January-April (Folder 3)
        - May-July (Folder 4)
        - August-December (Folder 5)
      - 1978
        - January-July (Folder 6)
        - July-December (Folder 7)
        - October-December (284, Folder 1)
      - 1979
        - January-March (Folder 2)
        - April-July (Folder 3)
        - July-December (Folder 4)
        - Various months (Folder 5)
      - A, 1977-78 (Folder 6)
      - ACUS sponsors, 1975 (Folder 7)
      - Atlantic Richfield Foundation, 1977-78 (Folder 8)
      - Atlantic Treaty Association, 1977 (Folder 9)
      - B, 1977 (Folder 10)
      - Burgess, W. Randolph, 1978 (Folder 11)
      - C
        - 1976-77 (285, Folder 1)
        - 1978 (Folder 2)
        - 1978-79 (Folder 3)
      - Corning Glass Works Foundation, 1978-79 (Folder 4)
      - Directors, 1977 (Folder 5)
      - F, 1977-78 (Folder 6)
      - Ford Foundation, 1976-77 (Folder 7)
      - Fowler, Henry H.
        - 1975 (Folder 8)
        - 1977-78 (Folder 9)
      - G, 1978-79 (Folder 10)
      - H
        - 1977 (Folder 11)
        - 1978-79 (Folder 12)
      - Huntley, James R., 1975-76 (Folder 13)
      - I, 1977-79 (286, Folder 1)
      - International Communication Agency, 1978-79 (Folder 2)
      - J, 1977-78 (Folder 3)
      - K, 1977-79 (Folder 4)
      - Kaplan Fund, 1975 (Folder 5)
      - Kettering, Charles F., Foundation, 1977 (Folder 6)
      - Krogh, Peter F., 1975 (Folder 7)
      - L, 1977-79 (Folder 8)
      - Letters to Directors, 1978 (Folder 9)
      - Lexington Book, 1976 (Folder 10)
      - Lilly Endowment, Inc., 1975-77 (Folder 11)
      - M
        - 1977 (Folder 12)
        - 1978 (Folder 13)
        - 1979 (Folder 14)
      - McDonnell Douglas Corporation, 1977-78 (Folder 15)
      - Mars Foundation, 1978 (Folder 16)
      - Marshall Foundation, 1975-76 (Folder 17)
      - Murphy, Robert, 1975-76 (Folder 18)
      - N, 1977-78 (Folder 19)
      - NATO, 1978 (287, Folder 1)
      - Nitze, Sullivan, 1976-78 (Folder 2)
      - P, 1978-79 (Folder 3)
      - Political Committee, 1978 (Folder 4)
      - Political Committee I, 1978 (Folder 5)
      - Political Committee II, 1978 (Folder 6)
      - Political Committee III, 1978 (Folder 7)
      - President and Vice President, 1976-77 (Folder 8)
      - R, 1977-79 (Folder 9)
      - Ranis, Gustav, 1977 (Folder 10)
      - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1976-77 (Folder 11)
      - S
        - 1977 (Folder 12)
        - 1978-79 (Folder 13)
      - Scaife Family Charitable Trusts, 1977 (Folder 14)
      - Segel, Joseph, 1977 (Folder 15)
      - T, 1976-79 (Folder 16)
      - Thank you letters, 1978 (Folder 17)
      - Tuthill, John W., 1975-76 (Folder 18)
      - U.S. Department of State
        - 1975-76 (288, Folder 1)
        - 1977 (Folder 2)
        - 1978 (Folder 3)
        - 1979 (Folder 4)
      - V, 1977-79 (Folder 5)
      - W, 1977-79 (Folder 6)
    - Director's help for financial support from corpora- (Folder 7)
      - tions, 1978
    - Distribution of "What Future for the UN?", 1978 (Folder 8)
    - East-West trade (Folder 9)
    - Energy Project (Folder 10)
    - Expense account, 1975 (Folder 11)
    - Exxon Corporation (Folder 12)
    - Food Project, 1978 (Folder 13)
    - Georgetown interns (Folder 14)
    - German Marshall Fund (Folder 15)
    - Gray Area
      - 1978 (Folder 16)
      - 1979 (289, Folder 1)
    - Hearst Foundation, 1978 (Folder 2)
    - Henry Luce Foundation (Folder 3)
    - International Monetary Affairs Report luncheon, Sep- tember, 14, 1978 (Folder 4)
    - International Monetary Problems Working Group, 1978 (Folder 5)
    - International Monetary Report, 1978 (Folder 6)
    - Kettering Foundation, 1978 (Folder 7)
    - Lilly Endowment, 1978 (Folder 8)
    - Mailing lists (Folder 9)
    - Media letter mailing, October 29, 1975 (Folder 10)
    - Memoranda to
      - ACUS staff, 1976 (Folder 11)
      - Board of Directors
        - 1978 (Folder 12)
        - 1979 (Folder 13)
      - Staff (Folder 14)
    - Middle East Working Group, 1979 (290, Folder 1)
    - Monetary Working Group, 1977-79 (Folder 2)
    - NATO
      - 1977 (Folder 3-4)
      - 1979 (Folder 5)
      - Grant requests, 1975-76 (Folder 6)
      - 30th anniversary (Folder 7-8)
    - Nuclear fuels, 1977-79 (291, Folder 1)
    - Nuclear fuels study, 1975-76 (Folder 2)
    - Policy papers distribution, 1977 (Folder 3)
    - Political Club, 1977-79 (Folder 4)
    - Political Working Groups (Folder 5)
    - Requests for financial support from corporations and foundations (Folder 6)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1978-79 (Folder 7)
    - Rockefeller Foundation
      - 1976 (Folder 8)
      - 1977-79 (Folder 9)
    - Scaife - Oceans Project, 1976 (Folder 10)
    - Scaife Foundation, 1978 (Folder 11)
    - School of Advanced International Studies (Johns Hopkins University), 1978-79 (Folder 12)
    - "Securing the Seas" (Folder 13)
    - "Securing the Seas" (292, Folder 1)
    - Security Working Group
      - 1977 (Folder 2)
      - 1978 (Folder 3-4)
      - 1979 (Folder 5)
    - "Some Remarks About the Relationship Between Political Science and Government Service,", 1978 (Folder 6)
    - Spain Project, 1978 (Folder 7)
    - Special Committee of the Atlantic Council on Inter- governmental Organization and Reorganization (Folder 8)
    - Special Committee on Improving Relations With Congress and the Executive Branch (Folder 9)
    - Speech, George Marshall Foundation, April 4, 1978 (Folder 10)
    - Sponsors, 1977-79 (Folder 11)
    - Staff memoranda, 1977 (293, Folder 1)
    - "Successor Generation,", 1979 (Folder 2)
    - Trade, 1976 (Folder 3)
    - Trade Project (Tokyo Rand), 1979 (Folder 4)
    - Trilateral Commission, 1976 (Folder 5)
    - Trip, Salt Lake City, October 24-25, 1978 (Folder 6)
    - United Nations Project, 1976 (Folder 7)
    - United Nations Working Group (Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 9-10)
  - Williams, Alan Lee, visit of, April 1972 (Folder 11)
  - Williamsburg Conference, June 5-8, 1966 (Folder 12)
  - Williamsburg Conference, June 5-8, 1966 (294, Folder 1-2)
  - Williamsburg meeting (Canadians), May 16, 1965 (Folder 3)
  - Wise Men (Folder 4)
  - Woodrow Wilson House (Folder 5)
  - Word index (Folder 6)
  - Working Group 7
    - General (Folder 7)
    - Means of securing political approval (Folder 8)
    - Meeting, July 16, 1975 (Folder 9)
  - Working Group on Coordination of Economic Policy (Folder 10)
  - Working Group on Development Problems (Folder 11)
  - Working Group on the United Nations (Folder 12)
  - Working Group on the United States and the United Nations (Folder 13)
  - Working Group on U.S. Policy Toward Developing Countries (Folder 14)
  - Working Groups
    - General (Folder 15)
    - Chairmen and rapporteurs, meeting, February 10, 1976 (Folder 16)
  - Wynn, Douglas (Folder 17)
  - Xerox
    - General (Folder 18)
    - University Microfilms (Folder 19)
  - Yale Review, 1961-62 (295, Folder 1)
  - Yankelovich, Daniel, "Jobs and Work," (Folder 2)
  - York University oral history, 1969-1970 (Folder 3)
  - Young Leaders Programme, Scaife proposal, 1972 (Folder 4)
  - Young Men's Christian Association, Center for International Management Studies (Folder 5)
  - Young Political Leaders
    - 1968 (Folder 6)
    - 1969 (Folder 7)
    - Expenses, 1966-67 (Folder 8)
  - Youth Committee, 1968 (Folder 9)
  - Youth Program, 1969 (Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 11-13)
  - Miscellaneous (296, Folder 1-5)
  - Miscellaneous (297, Folder 1-2)
- ATLANTIC CONGRESS, LONDON, JUNE 1959
  - General (297, Folder 3-5)
  - Administration and Congressional support (Folder 6)
  - Advisory Council, meeting, (Paris), November 16, 1958 (Folder 7)
  - Agenda (Folder 8)
  - Archbishop of York, "Spiritual Issues" (Folder 9)
  - Armand, Louis, "Scientific and Technical Cooperation" (Folder 10)
  - "Atlantic Congress Report" (Folder 11)
  - Barton, B. David and Martin Maddan, "Atlantic Institutions," (United Kingdom National Committee) (Folder 12)
  - Beloff, Max, "Atlantic Institutions, Present and Future" (Folder 13)
  - Beutler, Wilhelm, "Economic Policy Towards the Soviet Bloc" (Folder 14)
  - Biographies
  - Black, Cyril E. and Frederick Yeager, "Relations With the Communist Bloc" (Folder 15)
  - Bobba, Franco, "Some Considerations Regarding the 'Consequences of the Economic Integration of Western Europe'" (Folder 16)
  - "A British Look-Ahead on NATO - Conclusions of the Chatham House Study" (Folder 17)
  - Canadian Delegation, "Scientific and Technical Cooperation in the North Atlantic Community" (Folder 18)
  - Carpentier, General, "Report (French National Committee)" (Folder 19)
  - Choice of Assignment Committee (Folder 20)
  - Co-Chairmen Kefauver, Javits, Hays (298, Folder 1-2)
  - Cockcroft, John, "Research and Development" (Folder 4)
  - Committee allocations (Folder 5)
  - Committees and subcommittees
    - A, reports (Folder 6)
    - B, reports and resolutions (Folder 7)
    - C, reports and resolutions (Folder 8-10)
    - D, reports and resolutions (Folder 11)
    - E, reports and resolutions (Folder 12)
  - Comprehensive list of Congress documents (Folder 13)
  - Conclusions of the Princeton Conference on NATO, June 19-29, 1957 (Folder 14)
  - Congress functions, documents (Folder 15)
  - Congressional Record (Folder 16)
  - Correspondence
    - General (299, Folder 1)
    - Blaustein, Jacob (Folder 2)
    - Member nations (Folder 3-4)
  - Danielou, Jean, "The Spiritual and Cultural Values of the Atlantic Community" (Folder 5)
  - Declaration (Folder 6)
  - Declaration of Atlantic Unity (Folder 7)
  - Delany, George F. and Arthur Smith, "The European Common Market - Possible Implications for Canada and the United States" (Folder 8)
  - Delegates
    - Acceptances
      - A-H (Folder 9)
      - J-L (Folder 10)
      - M-R (Folder 11-12)
      - S-Z (Folder 13)
      - S-Z (300, Folder 1)
    - Agar, Herbert S. (Folder 2)
    - Alternate (Folder 3)
    - Anderson, Frederick L. (Folder 4)
    - Anderson, Mrs. J. P. (Folder 5)
    - Anderson, Victor E. (Folder 6)
    - Artz, Max (Folder 7)
    - Ashbrook, John M. (Folder 8)
    - Banning, Margaret Culkin (Folder 9)
    - Baumhart, Albert D. (Folder 10)
    - Bennett, Wallace F. (Folder 11)
    - Biographical sketches (Folder 12)
    - Blaustein, Jacob (Folder 13)
    - Bowie, Robert R. (Folder 14)
    - Brod, Mrs. Albert (Folder 15)
    - Brundage, Percival (Folder 16)
    - Burgess, Mrs. Randolph (Folder 17)
    - Canfield, Cass (Folder 18)
    - Canham, Erwin D. (Folder 19)
    - Chadwick, Stephen F. (Folder 20)
    - Coad, Merwin (Folder 21)
    - Cooper, John S. (Folder 22)
    - Crawford, Richard L. (Folder 23)
    - Cummings, Nathan (Folder 24)
    - Denton, Winfield (Folder 25)
    - Dinkelspiel, John W. (Folder 26)
    - Donovan, Hedley W. (Folder 27)
    - Draper, William H. (Folder 28)
    - Emmet, Christopher (Folder 29)
    - Finletter, Thomas K. (Folder 30)
    - Ford, George (Folder 31)
    - Foster, William (Folder 32)
    - Franklin, George S. (Folder 33)
    - Garwood, W. St. John (Folder 34)
    - Gavin, James M. (Folder 35)
    - Gordon, Lincoln (Folder 36)
    - Green, Edith S. (Folder 37)
    - Gross, Ernest A. (Folder 38)
    - Harris, Mrs. J. R. (Folder 39)
    - Hartley, Livingston (Folder 40)
    - Hayes, Albert J. (Folder 41)
    - Hays, Brooks (Folder 42)
    - Hays, Wayne (Folder 43)
    - Hemphill, Robert W. (Folder 44)
    - Hoffman, Claire G. (Folder 45)
    - Hofgren, Daniel W. (Folder 46)
    - Holt, Joe (Folder 47)
    - Hovde, Frederick L. (Folder 48)
    - Hoyt, Palmer (Folder 49)
    - Humphrey, Hubert (Folder 50)
    - Javits, Benjamin (Folder 51)
    - Javits, Jacob (Folder 52)
    - Johnson, Mordecai (Folder 53)
    - Joyce, Edmund (Folder 54)
    - Kallick, Sidney (301, Folder 1)
    - Kefauver, Estes (Folder 2)
    - Kerr, Clark (Folder 3)
    - Kestnbaum, Meyer (Folder 4)
    - Keyserling, Leon H. (Folder 5)
    - Kiley, Robert (Folder 6)
    - Kirk, Grayson (Folder 7)
    - Kissinger, Henry (Folder 8)
    - Kline, Allan B. (Folder 9)
    - Klutznick, Philip M. (Folder 10)
    - Koepfli, Joseph (Folder 11)
    - Kohn, Hans (Folder 12)
    - Lally, Francis J. (Folder 13)
    - Lancione, Nelson (Folder 14)
    - Lang, Reginald D. (Folder 15)
    - Linford, Velma (Folder 16)
    - List of (Folder 17-18)
    - List of possible (Folder 19)
    - Litchfield, Edward H. (Folder 20)
    - Lord, Oswald B. (Folder 21)
    - McCormick, Charles P. (Folder 22)
    - McGee, Gale W. (Folder 23)
    - McKinney, Robert (Folder 24)
    - Materials mailed to (Folder 25)
    - May, Catherine (Folder 26)
    - May, Stacy (Folder 27)
    - Meeman, Edward J. (Folder 28)
    - Moeller, Walter H. (Folder 29)
    - Moore, Ben T. (Folder 30)
    - Moore, Philip S. (Folder 31)
    - Moore, Walden (Folder 32)
    - Mowrer, Edgar (Folder 33)
    - Mueller, Reuben H. (Folder 34)
    - Murphy, Franklin D. (Folder 35)
    - Neal, Alfred C. (Folder 36)
    - Neuberger, Richard (Folder 37)
    - Newsom, Earl (Folder 38)
    - Newsom, Hershel (Folder 39)
    - Nitze, Paul (Folder 40)
    - Nuveen, John (Folder 41)
    - O'Brien, Dorothy (Folder 42)
    - Osborne, Lithgow (Folder 43)
    - O'Scannlain, Dairmuid (Folder 44)
    - Pace, Frank (Folder 45)
    - Patton, James G. (Folder 46)
    - Perkins, George W. (Folder 47)
    - Pool, David (Folder 48)
    - Porter, Henry H. (Folder 49)
    - Ragland, Mrs. Tom (Folder 50)
    - Reed, Philip D. (Folder 51)
    - Reid, Mrs. Ogden (Folder 52)
    - Rhyne, Charles S. (Folder 53)
    - Robinson, Mrs. W. L. (Folder 54)
    - Roebling, Mary G. (Folder 55)
    - Roper, Elmo (Folder 56)
    - Rose, Frank A. (302, Folder 1)
    - Rowan, Robert A. (Folder 2)
    - Sarnoff, David (Folder 3)
    - Scherman, Harry (Folder 4)
    - Schmidt, Adolph W. (Folder 5)
    - Seligman, Eustace (Folder 6)
    - Snyder, John I. (Folder 7)
    - Sonne, Hans C. (Folder 8)
    - Speiden, John G. F. (Folder 9)
    - Sproul, Robert B. (Folder 10)
    - Stevenson, Mrs. William E. (Folder 11)
    - Strausz-Hupe, Robert (Folder 12)
    - Streit, Clarence (Folder 13)
    - United States (Folder 14)
    - Wallhauser, George M. (Folder 15)
    - Wansker, Harry A. (Folder 16)
    - Warner, Earl E. (Folder 17)
    - Watson, Thomas J. (Folder 18)
    - Weaver, George (Folder 19)
    - White, Howard (Folder 20)
    - Whittemore, Laurence (Folder 21)
    - Williams, Harrison (Folder 22)
    - Witten, Sally S. (Folder 23)
    - Wright, William P. (Folder 24)
    - Zellerbach, Harold L. (Folder 25)
  - Dequae, A., "Western European Economic Intergration" (Folder 26)
  - Douglas, Lewis H. (Folder 27)
  - Eppstein, John, "Education" (Folder 28)
  - European-Atlantic Group, "Common Political and Economic Policies of the Atlantic Community Towards a Free and Uncommitted World" (Folder 29)
  - Expenses (Folder 30)
  - Fayat, H., "On National Cooperation" (Folder 31)
  - Federal Union Limited (United Kingdom National Committee), "Britain in the Common Market" (Folder 32)
  - Finances (Folder 33)
  - Furth, J. Herbert, "Freedom of Trade and Stability of Exchange" (Folder 34)
  - Further main points and trends from reports submitted (Folder 35)
  - Hartley, Livingston (Folder 36)
  - Hotel accomodations (Folder 37)
  - Information Bulletin
    - No. 1 (Folder 38)
    - No. 2 (Folder 39)
  - Ionides, M. G., "The Atlantic Community and the Middle East" (Folder 40)
  - Jackson, Lady, "Relations Between the Atlantic Countries and the Free and Uncommitted World" (303, Folder 1)
  - Jackson, Robert, "Atlantic-African Relations" (Folder 2)
  - Javits, Jacob
    - General (Folder 3)
    - "NATO Parliamentarians Conference Economic Committee Report" (Folder 4)
  - Johnston, Eric (Folder 5)
  - Kefauver, Estes (Folder 6)
  - Kissinger, Henry
    - "Strengthening the NATO Shield" (Folder 7)
    - Summary of papers by Buchau, Knorr, Kissinger, Carpen- tier and Van Zeeland (Folder 8)
  - Knorr, Klaus, "The Military Question" (Folder 9)
  - Labin, Suzanne, "The Techniques of Soviet Propaganda" (Folder 10)
  - Lodging and travel (Folder 11)
  - London Times editorial, "NATO's Next Ten Years,", June 6, 1959 (Folder 12)
  - Lord, Mrs. Oswald
    - "The Atlantic Institute" (Folder 13)
    - Draft of study paper for presentation by the American Committee on the Atlantic Institute (Folder 14)
  - Mailing lists (Folder 15)
  - Main points and trends from a few of the reports submitted (Folder 16)
  - Material for delegates (Folder 17)
  - Matthews, Bryan, "Science and Brain Warfare" (Folder 18)
  - Melen, Helen Moreau de, "Note on the Belgian Position in Matters of Defence" (Belgian National Committee) (Folder 19)
  - Members, list of (Folder 20)
  - Membership suggestions (Folder 21)
  - Memoranda to all delegates (Folder 22)
  - Memorandum to delegates going on charter plane, May 27, 1959 (Folder 23)
  - Moore, Ben, "Prosperity for All Atlantic Peoples" (Folder 24)
  - NATO Parliamentarians Conference
    - Paris, July 1958 (304, Folder 1)
    - Washington, D.C., June 1959 (Folder 2-4)
  - Netherlands National Committee
    - Draft resolution on an Atlantic Institute (Folder 5)
    - Outline for the consideration of the Netherlands' stand on moral and spiritual values of the Atlantic community (Folder 6)